Nicholas Roosevelt Papers
Nicholas Roosevelt Papers
- Writings
  - Books
    - A front row seat
      - Rough draft
        - "Manchuria", undated (Box 41)
        - "New York Times", undated (Box 41)
        - "Office of War Information", undated (Box 41)
        - "On the lecture front", undated (Box 41)
        - "Paris in World War I", undated (Box 41)
        - "T.R. and the 1912 campaign", undated (Box 41)
        - "Spanish interlude", undated (Box 41)
        - "Time to think", undated (Box 41)
        - "The Vienna mission", undated (Box 41)
        - "Visiting the front", undated (Box 41)
        - "With Wilson in Paris", undated (Box 41)
    - Good cooking
      - Author's copy with corrections, 1959; 5 folders (Box 42)
      - Blurb, undated (Box 42)
      - Drafts
        - Chapters 1-3, undated; 3 folders (Box 42)
        - Chapters 5-9, undated; 13 folders (Box 43)
        - Chapters 9-17, undated; 13 folders (Box 44)
        - Chapters 18, appendix, chapter outline, index, and fragments, undated; 6 folders (Box 45)
      - Galley proofs, 1959; 5 folders (Box 68)
      - Notes and research, undated (Box 45)
      - Recipes, undated; 3 folders (Box 45)
    - Hungary, unpublished
      - Drafts, undated; 2 folders (Box 45)
    - A new birth of freedom
      - Drafts, chapters 1-17, undated; 2 folders (Box 45)
    - The Philippines: a treasure and a problem
      - Foreword, undated (Box 46)
    - Stream of liberty
      - Chapter outline, undated (Box 46)
      - Early drafts
        - Foreword, introduction, table of contents, chapters 1-7, undated; 24 folders (Box 46)
        - Chapters 8-16, 1954; undated; 33 folders (Box 47)
        - Chapters 17-23, 1954; 23 folders (Box 48)
        - Chapters 24-28, 1954; 19 folders (Box 49)
        - Chapters 28-34, 1954; 16 folders (Box 50)
        - Chapter 34, epilogue, discards, and fragments, 1954; 11 folders (Box 51)
      - Final draft, undated; 2 folders (Box 51)
      - Final draft, undated; 4 folders (Box 52)
      - Final draft, 1954 version, 2 folders (Box 52)
      - Final manuscript, 1954; 2 folders (Box 53)
      - Final manuscript, 1954; 2 folders (Box 54)
      - First carbon, undated; 3 folders (Box 55)
      - Review copy with notes by Allan Nevins, 1963; 2 folders (Box 55)
      - Roots of American freedom version
        - Preface, chapters 1-27, 1964; 3 folders (Box 55)
        - Chapters 1-27, undated; 3 folders (Box 56)
        - Drafts, 1963; 3 folders (Box 56)
        - Final drafts, preface, chapters 1-21, 1964 (Box 56)
        - Final drafts, chapters 11-28, 1964 (Box 57)
      - Working copy
        - Chapters 1-29, footnotes, undated; 3 folders (Box 57)
    - Theodore Roosevelt: The man as I knew him
      - Corrections, undated (Box 58)
      - Early drafts
        - Table of contents, foreword, chapters 1-8, undated; 9 folders (Box 57)
        - Chapters 9-15, footnotes, undated; 8 folders (Box 58)
      - Galley proofs, undated (Box 58)
      - Illustration proofs, undated (Box 58)
      - Research notes
        - Adams, Henry, undated (Box 58)
        - Clippings, undated (Box 58)
        - "Extracts from TR speeches collected by Jacob Riis", undated (Box 59)
        - "Friends and associates", 1964-1965 (Box 59)
        - Hay, John, undated (Box 59)
        - Interviews, 1954-1955; 1964 (Box 59)
        - Lee, Alice, undated (Box 59)
        - Mahan, Alfred Thayer, 1965 (Box 59)
        - "Mind and character", 1965 (Box 59)
        - Quotes from NR's diary, 1965 (Box 59)
        - Quotes from TR's autobiography, undated (Box 59)
        - Republican party machine, undated (Box 59)
        - Roosevelt, Alice, 1964 (Box 59)
        - "TR as reformer", undated (Box 59)
        - Miscellaneous, 1964-1965; undated (Box 59)
    - United States foreign policy, 1916; unpublished (Box 59)
  - Book reviews, written by Nicholas Roosevelt (Box 59)
  - Book reviews, 1923-1941; written by Nicholas Roosevelt; 3 folders (Box 69)
  - Dispatches, United States embassy in Hungary to United States Department of State, 1931-1933; 3 folders (Box 69)
  - Editorials, 1917 (Box 59)
  - Editorials, 1927-1930; 3 folders (Box 69)
  - Letters to the editor, 1920-1921; 1956-1958 (Box 59)
  - Personal narratives and reflections
    - Account of Republican convention, 1912, undated; 3 folders (Box 59)
    - Arizona notes, 1913; typed and bound, includes photographs (Box 60)
    - Diary of far eastern journal, 1925; typed and bound (Box 60)
    - European trip, 1923-1924; 3 folders (Box 60)
    - The great rainbow natural bridge, undated (Box 60)
    - A history of a few weeks, 1919; typed and bound (Box 61)
    - Paris diary, volume 1, 1914-1916; typed and bound; 3 folders (Box 61)
    - Paris diary, volumes 1-2, 1914-1915; 10 folders (Box 62)
    - Through the painted desert to the North Rim of the Grand Canyon of Arizona, undated (Box 62)
    - Washington conference on limitations of naval armaments, 1921-1922 (Box 62)
    - Western trip, 1933
  - Speeches
    - "America in the making", 1938; delivered at the dedication of the Hungarian Garden, Cleveland (Box 62)
    - American journalism, undated (Box 62)
    - American motorhome exhibit opening speech, Philadelphia, PA, 1935 (Box 62)
    - Citations by the Kiwanis Club to certain New York newspapers, extension of remarks of Hon. Albert Hawkes, 1945 (Box 62)
    - "Conservation and informed public opinion", 1946; delivered at the North America Wildlife Conference (Box 62)
    - "Creative dollars abroad", 1940 (Box 62)
    - Foreign Policy Association remarks, 1936 (Box 63)
    - "Is a world system possible?", 1937
    - "Leaving the Philippines", 1935 (Box 63)
    - Leydon University lectures on American journalism, 1932 (Box 63)
    - Mills College lecture series, 1941; 2 folders (Box 63)
    - Nixon for president speech, circa 1968 (Box 63)
    - Radio address, 1940 (Box 63)
    - "The right to a free press", 1941 (Box 63)
    - Savings Banks Women's Association of the Metropolitan Area, New York, 1940 (Box 63)
    - "The shape of things to come: a look towards the year 2000", 1958; delivered at Monterey Peninsula College (Box 63)
    - "Should we stay in the Philippines", 1940 (Box 63)
    - Statement for Philippine Herald, 1930 (Box 63)
    - Statement for the United Press, 1935 (Box 63)
    - Town meeting of the air remarks, 1940 (Box 63)
    - "Two amazing years", 1935 (Box 63)
    - "Which road to peace now?", 1936 (Box 63)
    - "Who Owns America?", 1935 (Box 63)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Book chapter draft, "Season to taste", 1970
    - Memorandum of conversation with Admiral A. Andrews about the Normandie fire, 1942 (Box 63)
    - Notes
      - Far eastern trip, 1926 (Box 63)
      - Loans to foreign nations, undated (Box 69)
      - Mussolini, 1933 (Box 63)
      - On lace, undated (Box 63)
      - Vienna, 1919 (Box 63)
      - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 63)
    - Poem, "Ballad of English", 1914 (Box 63)
  - Writings by others
    - Addresses and speeches given by Leonard Wood, 1912; 1917-1918,; undated (Box 63)
    - Brief on behalf of Scenic Hudson Preservation Conference, reply on behalf of Scenic Hudson Preservation Conference, 1966 (Box 70)
    - Memorandum on Albania, by Franz Nopcsa, 1919 (Box 63)
    - Poems written by others, undated (Box 65)
    - Private approaches to the preservation of open land, by Russell L. Brenneman, 1967 (Box 70)